Sofya Nagaslaeva

sofyanagaslaeva@gmail.com, Silicon Valley, https://github.com/pazzissima 630-659-5847

Meticulous Front-End Developer with 8 years of experience building responsive web content in e-Commerce industry. Skilled in responsive design and development, A/B testing, personalization, page load optimization. Have knowledge of the best SEO practices, as well as Accessibility.

SPECIAL QUALIFICATIONS:

Languages, Technologies/Libraries: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query, ReactJS, BackboneJS

Tools: Git, Bitbucket, Optimizely, Tealium

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wine.com - San Francisco, CA 2021 - Present

Software Engineer

- > Profile Client performance and determine incremental ways to improve page load times.
- ➤ Lead engineering design for complicated feature requests.
- ➤ Identify and perform optimizations to reduce DOM and CSS bloat.
- > Perform Personalization and AB tests (Optimizely).
- ➤ Create pixel tags for tracking performance in Tealium for vendor partners.

Gap.com – San Francisco, CA 2014 – 2021

Web Content Developer

- ➤ Build and update <u>responsive</u> site content using HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, jQuery and JavaScript.
- ➤ Create HTML 5/CSS/JavaScript templates for online marketing initiatives.
- ➤ Perform Personalization and AB tests (Optimizely).
- > Communicate with multiple teams and business partners on a daily basis, facilitate standups.
- > Optimize site content to reduce page loading speed and to follow Accessibility standards.

Metrodigi – Larkspur, CA 2014 – 2014

JavaScript Engineer

- Built interactive widgets for tablets and ebooks using JavaScript, Mootools, jQuery, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Designed prototypes for widgets.
- ➤ Worked on a special project using AngularJS.
- > Researched possible solutions and developed concepts to meet the expectations of our clients.

Walmart.com – San Bruno, CA 2012 – 2014 Site Merchandising Operations Specialist/ Jr. Web Developer

- ➤ Led the team on optimizing and evolving page performance reports based on Omniture data. Created clickthrough maps.
- > Pulled and customized Omniture reports for top KPI's. Analyzed data from reports to make actionable steps to increase engagement and conversion.
- > Updated site content, wrote HTML, built search vanity links and created RSS feeds.

Limos.com – San Francisco, CA 2012 – 2012

SEO Copywriter (contractor)

- > Wrote concise and engaging website copy to increase conversion.
- ➤ Employed SEO strategy to offer descriptions in compliance with the latest Google Panda and Penguin updates.

Scrip Companies – Bolingbrook, Il 2011 – 2012

Assistant Product Manager

➤ Responsible for 200 wholesale accounts which generated over \$100 million in revenue. ➤ Placed products online, performed website cleanup, content management, internal link-building and worked cross-functionally to ensure consistent site standards.

Sears Holding - Hoffman, II 2009 - 2011

Web Merchandiser

- ➤ Managed online merchandising for the Men's apparel department, ensured all stock items were merchandised online.
- ➤ Developed methodology for naming products using SEO techniques, which translated into increased sales.

Optics Planet, Inc. – Northbrook, IL 2008 – 2009

Account Manager, Marketing Specialist

- ➤ Managed vendor comarketing administration: 5 accounts with \$6+ million in total sales for 2008.
- ➤ Performed strategic purchasing, forecasting, took advantage of special deals by analyzing sales, margin/markup and other reports.
- ➤ Utilized SEO and Web Analytics tools and techniques to enhance sites' optimization and increase conversion.

EDUCATION

General Assemb.ly, Web Development Immersive Program 2014 San Francisco, CA

Novosibirsk State University 2002-2007 Novosibirsk, Russia Master of Linguistics and Intercultural Communication